This is a work of fiction.
Underage drinking is strongly prohibited and illegal.
Scenes involving alcohol with forceful consumption
and shameful acts are not encouraged.
Please view this as a comedy.
Furthermore, all characters appearing
in this work are of legal age.
This work is an original copyrighted material
of the Content Provider. Unauthorized reproduction
or distribution of this work in any form or manner
is prohibited. Some viewers might find this work disturbing
as it may contain strong language, a degree of violence
or adult situations. Viewer discretion is advised.
Please watch it at your own risk.
The story, names, characters and incidents portrayed
in this work are fictitious. No identification with actual
persons, organizations, religions, places and products
is intended. The Content Provider, the producers
and related parties shall have no liability,
as to the accuracy, legality, safety or suitability
for any purpose of the information provided in this work.
The views and opinions expressed herein do not reflect
the views and opinions of the Content Provider,
or any of its affiliates, partners, subsidiaries, or Licensee.
Izu Spring Festival! Yay!
春[はる]:spring|New Year|prime (of one's life, etc.)||, 祭[まつり]:festival/feast
（一同）
伊豆(いず)春祭(はるさい)じゃ！　イエーイ！
♪～
Be passionate, my friends
Shine bright with the sun
Dive into the blue sky
And let summer take it all
GRAND BLUE DREAMING
Be passionate, my friends
Shine bright with the sun
Dive into the blue sky
And let summer take it all
An expanding ocean of possibilities
Summer is our amore
We'll swear to the crystal clear sky
Summer is in our hands
Be passionate, my friends
Shine bright with the sun
Dive into the blue sky
And let summer take it all
With a cheerful heart
Don't mess with me
Keep going even if you fall
And let summer take it all
～♪
OKONOMIYAKI
喜ぶ[よろこぶ]:to be delighted|to congratulate|to gratefully accept
（伊織(いおり)）なんて喜んだけど…
I was happy...
But it looks like we have to man the stall.
店番[みせばん]:store tending/salesperson
（耕平(こうへい)）俺たちは店番か
（千紗(ちさ)）お待たせしました
Thanks for waiting.
Thanks for your hard work!
疲れ[つかれ]:tiredness/fatigue, 調子[ちょうし]:tune|vein|condition||
（寿(ことぶき)）お疲れさん
調子はどうだ？
How's everything going?
All right.
ぼちぼち:little-by-little/gradually|not bad
ぼちぼちですね
It looks like we have a competitor.
商売敵[しょうばいがたき]:business rival/professional jealousy, みたい:-like/sort of/similar to
商売敵がいるみたいで
Oh, it's Tinkerbell.
（寿）ああ ティンカーベルか
Tinkerbell?
（伊織）ティンカーベルって？
It's a tennis club with lots of cute guys
and the highest ratio of girls.
美男[びなん]:handsome man
（寿）美男ぞろいで―
女子[じょし, おなご]:woman/girl, 女子[めこ, メコ]:vagina|girl, 比率[ひりつ]:ratio/proportion/percentage, ナンバー:number
女子比率ナンバー１の
テニサーだ
（伊織）へえ～
-How about trash?
-Pig's blood would be better.
生ゴミ[なまゴミ, なまごみ]:kitchen waste/food scraps/raw garbage, 豚[ぶた, ブタ]:pig (Sus scrofa domesticus)|fat person, 豚[とん]:pig/pork, 血[ち]:blood/consanguinity
生ゴミがいいか？
（伊織）豚の血だろ
Stop talking about
what you want to throw at them.
真顔[まがお]:serious look, 投げ込む[なげこむ]:to throw into, 話し合う[はなしあう]:to discuss/to talk together, やめる:to stop (an activity)/to cease|to cancel, やめる:to resign/to retire/to quit
真顔で何を投げ込むか
話し合うの やめて
Hey!
（梓(あずさ)）おーっす！
いやあ あっついね！
It's so hot!
（耕平･伊織）んーっ!?
You walked here?
歩き[あるき, ありき]:walk/walking|foot messenger (of a town, village, etc.)
歩きで来たのか？
I rode the bus part way.
途中[とちゅう]:on the way/en route|in the middle of
（梓）んにゃ 途中まではバス
How can you talk
like everything's normal?
いやいや:no!/no no!/no, not at all, いやいや:unwillingly/grudgingly|shaking head in refusal (to children), 普通[ふつう]:general|normally|local train, 会話[かいわ]:conversation, 始める[はじめる]:to start|to open (e.g. a store)|to start ...
いやいや
普通に会話 始められても
Please put this on.
とりあえず:first of all/at once|for now, 着る[きる]:to wear (in modern Japanese, from the shoulders down)/to put on|to bear (guilt, etc.), くださる:to give/to confer|to kindly do for one
とりあえず着てください
I'm okay.
別にいいよ
（千紗）ダメです
No!
Why are you dressed like that?
格好[かっこう, かっこ]:shape|appearance|state||
（伊織）その格好
どうしたんです？
My shirt just got drenched.
さっき:some time ago/just now, さっき:thirst for blood/bloodlust/determination to kill, ひっかける:to hang (something) on (something)/to throw on (clothes)|to hook
さっき そこで
ひっかけられちゃってね
Shouldn't you wash that?
洗う[あらう]:to wash|to inquire into|to purify (one's heart)|
（耕平）洗ったほうが
いいんじゃないですか？
It's going to get dirty again tonight
when you guys puke.
どうせ:anyhow/in any case|at best, 夜[よる, よ]:evening/night, 夜[や]:counter for nights, 吐く[つく]:to breathe out|to tell (a lie)|to vomit, 吐く[はく]:to vomit|to emit|to give (an opinion)|, 汚れる[けがれる]:to be violated/to be corrupted/to be polluted, 汚れる[よごれる]:to get dirty/to become dirty|to become sullied
どうせ 夜には
君らが吐いたもので汚れるし
夜[よる, よ]:evening/night, 夜[や]:counter for nights, どんな:what/what kind of|(with -temo, demo, etc.) any(body, thing, means, etc.), サバト:sabbath
（伊織）夜に
どんなサバトが待ってんだ
What's going to happen tonight?
This is the devil's festival.
まさに:exactly/surely|right then, 悪魔[あくま]:devil|Satan|Māra, 祭典[さいてん]:festival
（耕平）まさに悪魔の祭典だな
Why don't you go look for a T-shirt?
探す[さがす]:to search (for something desired, needed)/to look for|to search (for something lost)
Ｔシャツでも探してきたらどうだ？
I'm fine with this.
私は このままでもいいんだけど
That's a little too...
さすが:as one would expect|still/all the same, さすが:dagger
さすがに これはちょっと…
I guess you're right.
Come with me, Iori.
しかたない:it can't be helped/it's inevitable/it's no use, 一緒[いっしょ]:together|at the same time|same
しかたないなあ
じゃあ 伊織も一緒に行くよ
（伊織）は？　ちょ…
なんで俺も？
Wait, why do I have to go?
いらっしゃる:to come/to go|is (doing), いかが:how/in what way/how about
（学生）いらっしゃいませ
いかがですか～
Welcome! Please have a look!
うーん:hmm/well, 学園祭[がくえんさい]:school festival/campus festival, にぎやか:bustling/busy/lively
（梓）ん… うーん！
学園祭は にぎやかでいいねえ
School festivals are so lively. I love them!
You seem like the type who likes festivals.
梓[あずさ, し]:Japanese cherry birch (Betula grossa)|yellow catalpa (Catalpa ovata)|Japanese mallotus (Mallotus japonicus)||, 祭り[まつり]:festival/feast, 好き[すき]:liking/fondness/love, 好き[ずき]:-phil/-phile|being attractive (to), っぽい:-ish/-like|tossing something out
梓さん
祭り好きっぽいですもんね
Well, yeah.
まあねえ… あっ！
-Since we're talking about our interests...
-Yes?
好き[すき]:liking/fondness/love, 好き[ずき]:-phil/-phile|being attractive (to)
好きといえばさ
（伊織）はい？
What type of guys do you like?
どんな:what/what kind of|(with -temo, demo, etc.) any(body, thing, means, etc.), タイプ:type/kind/sort
伊織はどんな男がタイプなの
いきなり:abruptly/suddenly/all of a sudden
ブッ！
な… 何をいきなり
-What do you mean? That's random!
-Well...
同じ[おなじ, おんなじ]:same/identical|(usu. part of a 'nara' conditional) anyway, 趣味[しゅみ]:hobby/pastime|tastes, 持つ[もつ]:to hold (in one's hand)|to possess|to maintain||
いや ほらさ
同じ趣味を持つ人間としてね
You know, we're both into the same stuff...
（伊織）そういえば…
Now that you mention it...
Actually, I'm okay with both too.
実[じつ, じち]:truth|sincerity|content|, 実[み]:fruit|seed|(in broth) pieces of meat, vegetable, etc.|, どっち:which way/which direction|which one (esp. of two alternatives), イケる:to be good (at)|to look (taste, etc.) good|to hold one's liquor, 口[くち]:mouth|opening|mouth (of a bottle)||, 口[く, こう]:mouth/speech|counter for people or implements
（梓）実は私も
どっちもイケる口なんだ
Anyway, as for guys, I like Tokki.
ちなみ:association/link|pledge (esp. for marriage)
ちなみに私は 男ならトッキー
For girls, I like Nanaka.
華[はな]:flower|cherry blossom|beauty||
女なら 奈々華(ななか)がいいな
な… 奈々華さんですか？
Nanaka?
So how about you?
それで 伊織は？
へっ 何がです？
What do you mean?
What type do you like?
好き[すき]:liking/fondness/love, 好き[ずき]:-phil/-phile|being attractive (to), タイプ:type/kind/sort
（梓）好きなタイプ
誤解[ごかい]:misunderstanding, 解ける[とける]:to be solved|to loosen|to be removed (e.g. restrictions)|, 解ける[ほどける]:to come lose/to come untied|to loosen up (e.g. tension)
（伊織）誤解を解け！
Clear up the misunderstanding!
This is my only chance to tell her I'm not bi!
俺はバイじゃないと言うなら
ここしかない！
実[じつ, じち]:truth|sincerity|content|, 実[み]:fruit|seed|(in broth) pieces of meat, vegetable, etc.|
実はですね…
Actually...
（梓）ああ でもよかった
仲間がいて
I'm so glad I met someone like me.
Even I can't talk about this stuff
with other people.
いくら:how much?/how many?|even
いくら私でも―
絶対[ぜったい]:absolutely|absolute|absoluteness, 話せる[はなせる]:to be able to speak/to be able to talk|to be understanding
ほかの人には
絶対 こんなこと話せないもの
Help me, God!
助ける[たすける]:to save|to help|to aid|, 様[ざま]:mess|-ways|in the act of ...|, 様[さま]:Mr.|makes words more polite (usu. in fixed expressions)|state
（伊織）助けて 神様！
So, what's your type, Iori?
好み[このみ]:liking/taste/choice, 好み[よしみ, ぎ]:friendship/friendly relations/connection
それで伊織の好みは？
Hey, Kitahara.
（耕平）なあ 北原(きたはら)
（伊織）なんだ
What?
Why did Azusa say she wants to switch shifts
with me all of a sudden?
梓[あずさ, し]:Japanese cherry birch (Betula grossa)|yellow catalpa (Catalpa ovata)|Japanese mallotus (Mallotus japonicus)||
なぜ 梓さんは―
急[きゅう]:urgent|sharp|rapid||, 店番[みせばん]:store tending/salesperson, 替わる[かわる]:to succeed|to take the place of|to be exchanged
急に 俺と店番を替わると
言いだしたんだ？
I wonder...
なぜだろうな
-Just go off and have fun alone with Iori!
-Okay...
遊ぶ[あそぶ, あすぶ]:to play|to mess about (with alcohol, gambling, philandery, etc.)|to be idle||, 遊ぶ[すさぶ]:to grow wild/to rage|to do something one enjoys
（梓）いいから 伊織と２人で
遊んできなよ
（耕平）は… はあ
It's just that...
ただ あれだ
（耕平）ん？
I feel bad for doing this to you.
悪い[わるい]:bad|evil|unprofitable||, 悪い[にくい]:hateful/abominable|amazing
お前には
悪いことをしたと思ってる
You bastard. What did you get me into?
貴様[きさま]:you/you bastard|you, 巻き込む[まきこむ]:to roll up/to enfold|to involve, やがる:verb suffix indicating hatred and contempt, or disdain for another's action
貴様 俺を何に
巻き込みやがった！
It's so peaceful.
平和[へいわ]:peace/harmony, 平和[ピンフ, ピンホー]:concealed winning hand consisting of chows, a pair that isn't a value pair, and an open wait
いやあ しかし平和だな
It's because the others aren't here.
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder
先輩たちがいないからな
It's nice to spend time like this sometimes.
たまに:occasionally/once in a while
たまには こんな日もいいもんだ
It's Iori and Kohei!
（時田(ときた)）伊織に耕平じゃないか
You came at a good time.
いいところに来たな
（伊織）なんですか！
What?
We were talking about going out drinking
with some other clubs we interact with.
交流[こうりゅう]:(cultural) exchange/interchange|alternating current, サークル:group with a common interest (e.g. students)/club (e.g. company sports club)/circle
交流のあるサークルと
今晩[こんばん]:tonight/this evening, 合同[ごうどう]:combination/union|congruence, 飲む[のむ]:to drink|to smoke (tobacco)|to engulf||, 話[はなし]:talk/speech|discussions, 話[わ]:counter for stories, episodes of TV series, etc.
今晩 合同で
飲もうって話になってな
まさに:exactly/surely|right then, 合同[ごうどう]:combination/union|congruence, コンパ:party/social event/get-together
へえ まさに合同コンパですね
So it's a mixer.
So cute girls will be there?
女子[じょし, おなご]:woman/girl, 女子[めこ, メコ]:vagina|girl
じゃあ かわいい女子も!?
ハハハ:ha ha ha (laughter), 確認[かくにん]:confirmation/verification/validation, みてくれ:appearance/outward show
ハハハ それはあいつらに
確認してみてくれ
Check with them.
RUGBY CLUB
（ラグビー部員）ニン！
-Yeah!
-There definitely won't be any girls.
絶対[ぜったい]:absolutely|absolute|absoluteness, 女子[じょし, おなご]:woman/girl, 女子[めこ, メコ]:vagina|girl
（伊織）絶対 女子いねえ
So how about it?
（工藤(くどう)）それでどう？
Want to come over to our tent?
テント:tent
（部員）うちのテントに来ない？
It's going to be fun.
絶対[ぜったい]:absolutely|absolute|absoluteness, 楽しい[たのしい]:enjoyable/fun
絶対 楽しいからさあ
I'm not really interested...
ん～ そういうのはちょっとねえ
How many do you want to order?
注文[ちゅうもん]:order/request, 注文[ちゅうぶん]:annotation/explanatory note, 何枚[なんまい]:how many thin flat objects?
ご注文は何枚ですか
I'll buy five, tell me your Line ID.
枚[まい]:counter for flat objects (e.g. sheets of paper), 枚[びら, ビラ]:bill/handbill/flier, 買う[かう]:to buy|to value|to stir, 教え[おしえ]:teaching/instruction/teachings
じゃあ ５枚買うから
ＬＩＮＥ教え…
Hey.
楽しい[たのしい]:enjoyable/fun, 兄ちゃん[あんちゃん]:(my) older brother|sonny (with a nuance of suspicion)/lad, 兄ちゃん[にいちゃん]:familiar form of "older brother"
（耕平･伊織）よう
（伊織）楽しそうだな 兄ちゃん
You look like you're having fun.
Do you want to die?
地獄[じごく]:hell
お前らも地獄見るか？　あ？
-Friends of yours?
-Yeah.
知り合い[しりあい]:acquaintance, 一応[いちおう]:more or less|tentatively|just in case|
知り合い？
（千紗）一応…
We'll come invite you again.
誘い[さそい, いざない]:invitation/introduction|temptation
じゃあ また誘いに来るね
Throw the salt!
塩[しお, えん]:salt (i.e. sodium chloride)|salt (e.g. sodium chloride, calcium sulfate, etc.)|hardship|
塩まけ 塩！
Be gone, demons!
うせる:to disappear/to vanish, リア充[リアじゅう]:person who is satisfied with his or her real (offline) life
（耕平）うせろ リア充！
-Thanks for helping us out.
-Great.
助かる[たすかる]:to be saved|to escape harm|to be helped
２人とも 助かったよ
（耕平）フッ
（伊織）いえ
Do you want to switch shifts?
店番[みせばん]:store tending/salesperson, 交代[こうたい]:alternation/change/relief
それで 店番交代？
あ… そうですね
Okay.
Then let's have Chii-chan switch with Iori.
ちゃんと:diligently/seriously|perfectly, 交代[こうたい]:alternation/change/relief
じゃあ ちーちゃんと
伊織が交代しよっか
あ… はい
Okay.
Tell me how things went with Kohei.
教える[おしえる]:to teach|to tell|to preach
耕平とどうだったのか教えてよ
（伊織）ブーッ！
ん？　どうかした？
-What's wrong?
-Nothing.
いや その…
俺と千紗でやりますから
I'll work the stall with Chisa.
You can take a break.
梓[あずさ, し]:Japanese cherry birch (Betula grossa)|yellow catalpa (Catalpa ovata)|Japanese mallotus (Mallotus japonicus)||, 休憩[きゅうけい]:rest/break/recess, どうぞ:please/kindly|by all means
梓さんは休憩どうぞ
I've been working the whole time.
ずっと:continuously in some state (for a long time, distance)/throughout|much (better, etc.), 店番[みせばん]:store tending/salesperson
私 ずっと店番してたんだけど
Please!
頼む[たのむ]:to request|to call|to entrust to|
（伊織）頼む～
Sorry, Chisa.
悪い[わるい]:bad|evil|unprofitable||, 悪い[にくい]:hateful/abominable|amazing
悪いな 千紗
Come on. Tell me why.
まったく:really/truly|indeed
まったく…
で なんで？
Well, how should I put it...
なんという:how (beautiful, etc.)
ああ… なんというかだな
I want to avoid being left alone with Azusa.
梓[あずさ, し]:Japanese cherry birch (Betula grossa)|yellow catalpa (Catalpa ovata)|Japanese mallotus (Mallotus japonicus)||, 避ける[さける, よける]:to avoid (physical contact with)|to avoid (situation)|to ward off
梓さんと２人になるのを
避けたいんだ
Well, Azusa is pretty, after all.
ふうん:misfortune/bad luck/ill luck, ふうん:hmm/well ...|roughly
ふうん まあ―
梓[あずさ, し]:Japanese cherry birch (Betula grossa)|yellow catalpa (Catalpa ovata)|Japanese mallotus (Mallotus japonicus)||, 美人[びじん]:beautiful woman
梓さん 美人だもんね
（伊織）は？
You get nervous when you're with her, right?
緊張[きんちょう]:tension/mental strain/nervousness
２人きりだと緊張するんでしょ？
Well, I guess I do get nervous...
緊張[きんちょう]:tension/mental strain/nervousness
まあ 緊張するといえば
するんだが…
What's with that answer?
玉虫色[たまむしいろ]:iridescent|equivocal|variable meaning, 返事[へんじ]:reply/answer/response
何？　その玉虫色の返事
Welcome!
いらっしゃる:to come/to go|is (doing)
いらっしゃいませ
-Thanks.
-One moment please.
まいど:each time/always|thank you for your continued patronage, 少々[しょうしょう]:just a minute/small quantity, くださる:to give/to confer|to kindly do for one
（伊織）はーい まいど
（千紗）少々 お待ちください
What time is the women's beauty pageant?
ミスコン:beauty contest to name Miss ..., 何時[いつ]:when/how soon, 何時[なんじ, なんどき]:what time?
ところで
ミスコンは何時なんだ？
It's at 4. The award ceremony is tomorrow.
表彰[ひょうしょう]:public acknowledgment/public acknowledgement/public recognition, 式[しき]:equation|ceremony|style|, 明日[あした, あす]:tomorrow|near future
４時からで 表彰式が明日
Ours is tonight.
今晩[こんばん]:tonight/this evening
こっちは今晩だ
-Thanks for waiting. 600 yen, please.
-Okay.
円[えん]:yen/Japanese monetary unit|circle, 円[まる]:circle|entirety|money||
（千紗）お待たせしました
600円になります
（客）は… はい
-Thank you!
ありがとう:Thank you/Thanks, ござる:to be
（伊織･千紗）
ありがとうございました
PEEK-A-BOO
Shouldn't you start getting ready?
そろそろ:slowly/quietly|soon, 準備[じゅんび]:preparation/setup/arrangements
そろそろ 準備したほうが
いいんじゃ？
I was just going to go like this.
私はこのまま出るつもりだけど
（千紗）うっ！
（梓）ダメよ ちーちゃん
You can't do that, Chii-chan.
You're cute, so we have to get
lots of people to notice you.
華[はな]:flower|cherry blossom|beauty||
（奈々華）
かわいい千紗ちゃんを―
たくさん:a lot/lots|enough, もらう:to receive/to take|to get somebody to do something
たくさんの人に見てもらわなきゃね
This is our chance.
せっかく:stone burial chamber, せっかく:with trouble/at great pains|rare, チャンス:chance/opportunity
せっかくのチャンスだものね
頑張る[がんばる]:to persevere|to insist that|to remain in a place
（伊織）頑張ってな～
Good luck.
Where did Kotegawa go?
古手川(こてがわ)はどこへ？
To do her makeup
for the beauty pageant.
ミスコン:beauty contest to name Miss ..., 化粧[けしょう, けわい]:make-up/makeup/cosmetics
ミスコンのための化粧だとさ
Are you having them do yours next?
次[つぎ]:next/following|stage, 次[じ]:next|hypo- (i.e. containing an element with low valence)|order, もらう:to receive/to take|to get somebody to do something
その次は
お前もやってもらうのか？
Are you trying to embarrass me?
辱める[はずかしめる]:to put to shame/to humiliate|to rape, 気[き]:spirit|nature|motivation||, 気[げ]:seeming/giving the appearance of/giving one the feeling of
（伊織）お前はどこまで
俺を辱める気なんだ！
You have long hair.
You should dress up as a girl!
髪[かみ]:hair (on the head), 女装[じょそう]:female clothing/wearing female clothing/cross dressing (for a man)
髪長いんだから
お前が女装しろよ！
枠[わく]:frame|border|limit, ふさわしい:appropriate/adequate/suitable
（耕平）イヤだ お前にこそ
ネタ枠はふさわしい
No! You're the one entering the joke category!
（伊織）んだと この～
Hey! We're going to close the stall
and go watch!
おーい:hey!/oi!|I, 一旦[いったん]:once|for a short time|one morning, 店[みせ]:store/shop/establishment, 店[てん]:-store/-shop, 閉める[しめる]:to close/to shut, 野音[やおん]:outdoor concert hall/band shell/bandstand
（寿）おーい
一旦 店閉めて野音に行くぞ！
IZU UNIVERSITY SPRING FESTIVAL
WOMEN'S BEAUTY PAGEANT
There's a lot of people here.
結構[けっこう]:splendid|sufficient|well enough||
（伊織）結構 人が入ってますね
This is the main event, along with the male pageant.
そりゃ:very/extremely|that is, ステージ:stage, 目玉[めだま]:eyeball|special feature|special program|
そりゃ これと男(だん)コンが
ステージの目玉だからな
We're going on stage in front of
such a huge crowd?
大勢[おおぜい, たいぜい]:crowd of people/great number of people|in great numbers, 大勢[たいせい]:general trend/current thought
こんな大勢の前に出るのか
You'll be fine.
You'll be dressed as a guy.
格好[かっこう, かっこ]:shape|appearance|state||
お前はいいだろ
男の格好なんだから
You're not happy in the joke category?
枠[わく]:frame|border|limit, 不満[ふまん]:dissatisfaction/displeasure/discontent
ネタ枠が不満なのか？
必要[ひつよう]:necessary/needed|necessity, 感ずる[かんずる]:to feel/to sense
というか
出る必要を感じないというか
I don't understand why I have to enter.
What are you talking about?
Look, Iori.
何を言う 見てみろ 伊織
（伊織）はい？
AINA YOSHIWARA
(20 YEARS OLD)
アッハッハ:a-ha-ha (laughing loudly)
（愛菜(あいな)）アッハッハ～
That's a lot of makeup.
（耕平･伊織）ケ… ケバい
The other clubs are also entering the joke category.
サークル:group with a common interest (e.g. students)/club (e.g. company sports club)/circle, 枠[わく]:frame|border|limit, 用意[ようい]:preparation/arrangements/provision
（時田）ほかのサークルだって
ネタ枠を用意しているだろ？
Aina-chan, you're so cute!
（部員）愛菜ちゃん かわいいよ～
Hi!
ハア～イ！
（愛菜）あっ！
（耕平）えっ!?
ン… チュッ
（耕平）ケバッ…
（男性たち）おお～
（千紗）んっ…
She looks harsh.
感じ[かんじ]:feeling/sense/impression
（伊織）なんか
トゲトゲしい感じだな
Is she mad?
怒る[おこる, いかる]:to get angry|to tell someone off|to be angular
（耕平）あれは怒ってるのか？
Please say your name and your club.
所属[しょぞく]:attached to/belong to/member, サークル:group with a common interest (e.g. students)/club (e.g. company sports club)/circle, どうぞ:please/kindly|by all means
（司会者）
所属サークルとお名前をどうぞ
I'm Chisa Kotegawa from Peek-a-Boo.
Peek a Boo(ピーカブー)の
古手川千紗です
I think she's nervous.
たぶん:informing, たぶん:perhaps/probably|generous, ありゃ:oh/ah/I'll be darned, 緊張[きんちょう]:tension/mental strain/nervousness, 顔[かお, がん]:face|look|honor|, 顔[かんばせ]:countenance/visage|face
（伊織）いや たぶん
ありゃ緊張してる顔だ
Kotegawa's so awkward.
不器用[ぶきよう]:clumsy|tactless|mean
（耕平）不器用だな 古手川
This is bad.
マズい:unappetising|unskillful|ugly|
しかし マズいな
At this rate, she might lose.
負ける[まける]:to lose|to succumb|to be inferior to||, 可能性[かのうせい]:potentiality/likelihood/possibility
このままだと
負ける可能性もありえるぞ
-What's your hobby?
-Diving.
趣味[しゅみ]:hobby/pastime|tastes, ダイビング:diving
（司会者）ご趣味は？
（千紗）ダイビングです
Kohei, do you have any ideas?
耕平 何か手はないか？
You know lots about these games, right?
ゲーム:game, 詳しい[くわしい]:detailed/full|knowing very well
“その手のゲーム”とかに
詳しいんだろ？
Well, you're right. I do know a lot...
確か[たしか]:sure|reliable|If I'm not mistaken, ゲーム:game, 詳しい[くわしい]:detailed/full|knowing very well
まあ 確かに “その手のゲーム”
には詳しいですが…
If you want to make a quiet girl shine,
you make her smile.
無口[むくち]:reticence/taciturnity|reticent, 無口[むこう]:astomatous, キャラ:(fictional) character, 輝く[かがやく]:to shine/to glitter/to sparkle
ああいう無口なキャラが
輝くとなると―
めった:thoughtless/reckless|seldom (with neg. verb), 見せる[みせる]:to show/to display, 笑顔[えがお]:smiling face/smile
めったに見せない笑顔ですかね
Brother Kohei...
おにいちゃん:familiar form of "older brother"|form of address for young adult male/mister
（あや）耕平…
おにいちゃん…
Smile?
笑顔[えがお]:smiling face/smile
笑顔かあ
It's hard to make Chisa smile.
笑う[わらう]:to laugh|to smile|to sneer|, 至難[しなん]:most difficult/next to impossible, 業[ごう]:karma (i.e. actions committed in a former life), 業[わざ]:deed/act/work
千紗を笑わせるのは
至難の業だぞ
If we smile, maybe she'll smile too.
笑う[わらう]:to laugh|to smile|to sneer|, みせる:to show/to display
こっちが笑ってみせたら
つられて笑うんじゃないか？
Let's try that!
それでいこう！
Chisa!
（一同）千紗～！
ニヒヒヒ…
No! We made it worse!
いかん:Italian warship, いかん:ancient headgear showing rank, 逆効果[ぎゃくこうか, ぎゃっこうか]:opposite effect/adverse effect/backfiring
（寿）いかん 逆効果だ
She shouldn't make that face
in front of the crowd.
客[きゃく, かく]:guest/visitor|customer, 客[まろうど, まろうと]:visitor from afar/guest, 顔[かお, がん]:face|look|honor|, 顔[かんばせ]:countenance/visage|face
（伊織）あれは 客前で
やっちゃダメな顔ですね
Do you have any other ideas?
（時田）ほかには何かないか？
How about showing them her bashful side?
恥じらう[はじらう]:to feel shy/to be bashful/to blush
あとはまあ 恥じらいでしょうか
恥じらい[はじらい]:shyness
恥じらいかあ
Bashful?
How can we do that?
んなもん どうやればいいんだ
Based on what I know...
展開[てんかい]:development|expansion|expansion
俺の知ってる展開では…
Can you introduce your club?
サークル:group with a common interest (e.g. students)/club (e.g. company sports club)/circle, 紹介[しょうかい]:introduction/presentation/referral
（司会者）
それでは サークル紹介を
Chisa!
千紗～！
ん？
WE LOVE CHISA
She's not being bashful.
恥じらう[はじらう]:to feel shy/to be bashful/to blush
恥じらわないな
That's weird. Normally...
おかしい:funny/amusing|strange, 普通[ふつう]:general|normally|local train
おかしいですね 普通はここで…
Why are you doing this?
なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation, 格好[かっこう, かっこ]:shape|appearance|state||
（さくら）な…
なんて格好してるのよ
She would say that.
となるはずなんですか
She looks like she's looking at trash.
Our plan failed.
（伊織）あれはゴミを見る目だ
失敗[しっぱい]:failure/mistake/blunder
（寿）これも失敗だな
-There's only one thing left.
-What is it?
（耕平）となると あとはアレだな
服装[ふくそう]:garments/attire
（伊織）アレとは？
（耕平）今日の服装
-Today's outfit.
-Okay. We're lifting up her skirt.
スカート:skirt
ＯＫ スカートめくりだな
フッ 言うまでもなかったな
I didn't even have to say it.
伝わる[つたわる]:to be handed down/to be introduced/to be transmitted
なぜ伝わるんだ
How come he knew?
You have weird ideas.
発想[はっそう]:idea/conception|expression, おかしい:funny/amusing|strange
お前らの発想はおかしい
How are we going to lift up her skirt?
問題[もんだい]:question (e.g. on a test)|problem (e.g. societal, political)|question (i.e. doubt)||, めくる:to turn over/to turn pages of a book|to tear off
（伊織）問題は
どうやってめくるかだが…
-Look at these!
-Bouncy balls?
スーパー:super, ボール:ball
（耕平）これを見ろ！
（時田）スーパーボール？
Are you going to throw them at her feet?
足元[あしもと, そっか]:at one's feet|gait|most recent|, 投げる[なげる]:to throw/to cast away|to face defeat
千紗の足元に投げるのか
恥ずかしい[はずかしい]:shy/ashamed|disgraceful
（女の子）きゃっ！
恥ずかしいよう
This is so embarrassing!
I get it.
It's what kids do to tease each other.
なるほど:I see/That's right!/Indeed, 小学生[しょうがくせい]:elementary school student/primary school student/grade school student, いたずら:mischief/prank|pastime, いたずら:useless/vain/aimless
（寿）なるほど
小学生のいたずらであるやつだな
This would make Chisa really mad.
相当[そうとう]:befitting|considerable|to be worthy of||, 怒りを買う[いかりをかう]:to rouse anger/to provoke wrath/to offend
しかし これは
相当 千紗の怒りを買うんじゃ
You're right.
She might kill you, Iori.
実行犯[じっこうはん]:perpetrator
そうだな 実行犯の伊織が
殺されかねん
Who said I'm the one who's going to do it?
確定[かくてい]:decision/settlement|definition
なぜ 俺がやるって
確定しているんですかね
It's Chisa.
So you should do it.
千紗ちゃんといえば伊織だろ
Let's decide with rock, paper, scissors!
せめて:at least/at most, せめて:offense/offence/method of attack, ジャンケン:rock, paper, scissors game, 決める[きめる]:to decide|to clinch (a victory)|to persist in doing||
せめてジャンケンで決めましょうよ
-I have a better idea.
-What is it?
もっと:(some) more/even more/longer, 方法[ほうほう]:method/process/manner
もっと いい方法がある
（寿）というと？
Let's all throw them at the same time
so she doesn't know who did it.
全員[ぜんいん]:all members (unanimity)/all hands/the whole crew, 一斉[いっせい]:simultaneous/all at once, 投げる[なげる]:to throw/to cast away|to face defeat
全員で一斉に投げて―
実行犯[じっこうはん]:perpetrator, 特定[とくてい]:specific/particular|specifying
実行犯を特定させない
というのはどうだろうか
That's not a bad idea, coming from you.
考え[かんがえ]:thinking|idea|intention||
お前にしては
いい考えじゃないか
Then, let's go with that.
（時田）じゃあ それでいくか
（一同）フッ…
Ready! One, two...
いくぞ！　いっせーの―
せっ！
（伊織）どりゃあ！
Take this!
うっ！
（男性たち）おお～！
-Nice!
-Do it!
感じ[かんじ]:feeling/sense/impression, たたみかける:to press for an answer/to shower questions on someone
（耕平）よし いい感じだ！
（時田）たたみかけろ！
おうっ！
Nice control, Iori!
ナイス:nice, コントロール:control
（寿）ナイスコントロールだ 伊織
You're the only one who can do this kind of thing!
やはり:too/also|still
（時田）やはり こんなことが
できるのはお前しかいない
任せる[まかせる]:to entrust (e.g. a task) to another|to passively leave to someone else's facilities|to leave to take its natural course||, くださる:to give/to confer|to kindly do for one
ヒィ～！　任せてください！
Leave it to me!
え？
Are you okay?
えーっと:let me see/well/errr ...
（司会者）え… えーっと
大丈夫でしょうか
Why aren't you guys throwing them?
投げる[なげる]:to throw/to cast away|to face defeat
な… なんで
みんな投げてないんですか!?
（千紗）うう…
あ… ああ…
ううう…
Hurry up and let her
execute you.
処刑[しょけい]:execution
さっさと処刑されたらどうだ？
You bastard! You act like you're innocent!
てめえ:you (used by young males)|oneself, ひと事[ひとごと, たにんごと]:other people's affairs/somebody else's problem
てめえ ひと事だと…
（枝が揺れる音）
（耕平）ん？
お化け[おばけ]:goblin/monster|ghost
うおっ！　お化け！
A ghost!
You were in the women's beauty pageant...
Cakey?
確か[たしか]:sure|reliable|If I'm not mistaken, ミスコン:beauty contest to name Miss ...
お前 確かミスコンにいた…
ケバ子
（耕平）え？
Hey, you...
ねえ あんた
（耕平）な… なんだよ
What is it?
Please go out with me.
つきあう:to associate with/to keep company with|to go along with, つきあう:to poke each other/to jab each other
私とつきあってよ
（耕平）はあ？
GRAND BLUE DREAMING
Go out with you? You and me?
つきあう:to associate with/to keep company with|to go along with, つきあう:to poke each other/to jab each other
（耕平）つきあうって…
俺とお前が？
Yeah. Got a problem with that?
文句[もんく]:complaint/grumbling|phrase
そう 文句ある？
Hold on! I don't even know your name.
相手[あいて]:companion|other party|opponent (sports, etc.)
待ってくれ 名前も知らん相手に…
Aina Yoshiwara, a freshman at
Oumi Women's University. Okay?
青女[あおおんな]:young girl unused to the ways of the world
吉原(よしわら)愛菜 青女(あおじょ)の１年
これでいい？
Not at all.
全く[まったく]:really|indeed|good grief (expression of exasperation)
全くよくない
Congratulations, Kohei.
I hope you live happily ever after.
おめでとう:congratulations!/an auspicious occasion!, おめでとう:Japanese sweets made with glutinous rice and azuki bean paste, 末[うら]:top end/tip, 末[うれ]:new shoots/new growth (of a tree), 永い[ながい]:long (distance)|long (time)/lengthy, 幸せ[しあわせ, しやわせ]:happiness/good fortune/luck
おめでとう 耕平
末永く幸せにな
Where do you think you're going?
どこへ行こうというのかね？
I thought you two should spend time alone.
若い[わかい]:young|immature|low (number)
あとは若いお２人でと思って…
状況[じょうきょう]:state of affairs (around you)/situation/circumstances, 置く[おく]:to put|to leave (behind)|to establish (an organization, a facility, a position, etc.)||, なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation, 持つ[もつ]:to hold (in one's hand)|to possess|to maintain||
（耕平）この状況で置いてくなんて
人の心を持っていないのか
How can you leave me alone like this?
That's so inhumane!
You left me to die just now, you loser.
さっき:some time ago/just now, さっき:thirst for blood/bloodlust/determination to kill, 平然[へいぜん]:calm/composed/cool, 切り捨てる[きりすてる]:to cut down|to truncate|to omit
ついさっき 俺を
平然と切り捨てたクズが何を言う
Never mind.
（愛菜）もういい
What was that about?
なんだったんだ
So that's where you guys were.
所[ところ, とこ]:place|address|district||, 所[しょ]:counter for places
お前ら こんな所にいたのか
What were you doing?
何してたんだ？
-Experiencing youth.
-What?
青春[せいしゅん]:youth/springtime of life/adolescent, そりゃ:very/extremely|that is
青春… ですかね
（時田）なんだそりゃ
Cheers!
（一同）カンパーイ！
人違い[ひとちがい]:mistaking one person for another/(case of) mistaken identity
あ… 人違いです
-You've got the wrong guy.
-I haven't said anything yet.
まだ何も言ってないんだけど
It's not what you think!
I did it to draw out your charm!
魅力[みりょく]:charm/fascination/glamour, 引き出す[ひきだす]:to pull out/to take out/to draw out
違うんだ 千紗！　あれは
お前の魅力を引き出すためで
I wanted to show the audience
how cute you are!
見せる[みせる]:to show/to display
つまり かわいい千紗を
見せたいという…
ハァ… もういいわ
That's enough.
許す[ゆるす]:to permit|to exempt (from fine)|to confide in|
え… 許してくれるのか？
You're forgiving me?
I owe you one.
貸し[かし]:loan|favor|creditor
貸しにしとく
Really? Thanks, Chisa!
ありがとう:Thank you/Thanks
マジか！
ありがとう 千紗！
To show my appreciation,
I'll buy you some sexy underwear.
お礼[おれい, おんれい]:thanks|manners|bow||, 今度[こんど]:this time|next time|recently, ちょい:heirship, ちょい:just a minute/short time|somewhat, 色気[いろけ]:colouring|sex appeal (esp. women)|romance|, 下着[したぎ]:underwear, 買う[かう]:to buy|to value|to stir
お礼に今度 もうちょい色気のある
下着 買ってやるからな
She said she'd forgive you. What a waste.
せっかく:stone burial chamber, せっかく:with trouble/at great pains|rare, 許す[ゆるす]:to permit|to exempt (from fine)|to confide in|, もらう:to receive/to take|to get somebody to do something
（耕平）せっかく
許してもらったのに…
So you looked!
You pervert!
助平[すけべ, すけべい]:lewdness/lewd person/lecher
（寿）というか 見るところは
見てたんだな この助平(すけべえ)め
Chisa?
千紗？
Are you really mad?
もしかし:perhaps/maybe/by some chance, 怒る[おこる, いかる]:to get angry|to tell someone off|to be angular
もしかして
すんげえ怒ってます？
SHOCHU
I'll drink it.
いただく:to receive/to get|to eat
いただきます
ごちそう:feast/treating (someone)|to treat (someone, e.g. to a meal)
うっ… ごちそうさまでした
Thanks for the drink.
He drank two liters.
リットル:litre, くらい:dark/gloomy|dark (in colour), くらい:approximately/about|to (about) the extent that, やがる:verb suffix indicating hatred and contempt, or disdain for another's action
２リットルくらい
いきやがった
That took some guts.
根性[こんじょう]:willpower/guts|character, 見せる[みせる]:to show/to display
根性見せたな
Impressive, Iori!
さすが:as one would expect|still/all the same, さすが:dagger
さすが伊織だ
I'm back.
ただいま:Here I am/I'm home!|presently
ただいま
You're late.
遅い[おそい]:slow|late (e.g. "late at night")|too late|
（時田）遅かったな
Did something happen?
（寿）何かあったのか？
Some guy was hitting on me.
しつこい:insistent/obstinate|too rich (taste, etc.), ナンパ:seducer/smooth talker/ladies' man
いやあ しつこい
ナンパにあっちゃってね
Are you okay?
大丈夫だったんですか？
うん まあね
Yeah.
You promised earlier today, right?
昼[ひる]:noon|daytime|lunch, 約束[やくそく]:promise|convention|destiny
ほら 昼に約束したじゃない
I already have plans.
先約[せんやく]:previous engagement/prior contract
先約があるんだよね
It's okay. You're talking about those guys, right?
じゃん:isn't it, 先約[せんやく]:previous engagement/prior contract, どうせ:anyhow/in any case|at best
いいじゃん 先約ってどうせ
あいつらでしょ？
Come on.
ったく:good grief (expression of exasperation)
（梓）ったく
MEN'S BEAUTY PAGEANT
REGISTRATION DEADLINE: 30 MINUTES LEFT
ミスター:mister/Mr, コンテスト:contest
（梓）ねえ 君
ミスターコンテストには出ないの？
Aren't you going to enter the men's pageant?
今年[ことし, こんねん]:this year, 後輩[こうはい]:junior (at work, school, etc.)/younger people/younger student, 任せる[まかせる]:to entrust (e.g. a task) to another|to passively leave to someone else's facilities|to leave to take its natural course||, 気[き]:spirit|nature|motivation||, 気[げ]:seeming/giving the appearance of/giving one the feeling of
ん？　今年は
後輩に任せる気だけど
I'm letting the younger students
do it this year.
Did you want to see me compete?
もしかし:perhaps/maybe/by some chance
もしかして
俺が出るとこ 見たい？
Yes! I do!
I'll cheer for you in the front row.
最[さい]:the most/the extreme|prime, 前列[ぜんれつ]:front row, 応援[おうえん]:aid/assistance/help
見たい 見たい
最前列で応援する
Well, if you insist...
しかたない:it can't be helped/it's inevitable/it's no use
しかたないなあ…
I ran away while he was registering.
登録[とうろく]:registration/accession/register, 間[あいだ, あわい]:space (between)|time (between)|span (temporal or spatial)||, 間[ま]:time|space|room, 逃げる[にげる]:to escape/to run away
って言って
登録してる間に逃げてきた
Impressive, Azusa.
さすが:as one would expect|still/all the same, さすが:dagger, 梓[あずさ, し]:Japanese cherry birch (Betula grossa)|yellow catalpa (Catalpa ovata)|Japanese mallotus (Mallotus japonicus)||
さすが梓さん
-Are you going to cheer for him?
-Of course not.
応援[おうえん]:aid/assistance/help
応援すんのか？
じゃん:isn't it
するわけないじゃん
（耕平）ひでえ
-That's terrible.
-I'm glad you're safe.
無事[ぶじ]:safety/peace/quietness
まあ 無事で何よりだ
You're in time for our gathering.
集合[しゅうごう]:gathering/assembly|set, 間に合う[まにあう]:to be in time for|to serve (suit, meet) the purpose/to be good enough
集合にも間に合ったしな
That's right.
そだね～
集合[しゅうごう]:gathering/assembly|set
（伊織）へ？　集合？
Gathering?
集合[しゅうごう]:gathering/assembly|set
（伊織）へ？　集合？
We're here, just like we promised!
約束[やくそく]:promise|convention|destiny, どおり:in accordance with/following|roughly, 遊びに来る[あそびにくる]:to come and stay/to drop in/to visit
（ラグビー部員）
よう 約束どおり遊びに来たぞ
約束[やくそく]:promise|convention|destiny, どおり:in accordance with/following|roughly, 遊びに来る[あそびにくる]:to come and stay/to drop in/to visit
（ラグビー部員）
よう 約束どおり遊びに来たぞ
RUGBY CLUB
イヤー:ear
（伊織･耕平）イヤー！
うれしい:happy/glad/pleasant, 声を上げる[こえをあげる]:to raise one's voice
（ラグビー部員）そう うれしそうな
声を上げるな 伊織 耕平
Contain your excitement,
Iori and Kohei!
This drinking party is crazier than usual.
以上[いじょう]:not less than|beyond ... (e.g. one's means)|above-mentioned||, すげえ:incredible/unbelievable, 飲み会[のみかい]:drinking party/get-together
いつも以上に
すげえ飲み会だよなあ
Oh, that's...
（伊織）ん？　あれは…
（耕平）うっ！
You guys...
あんたら…
ちょっ あんた…
You...
Cakey! Wait! Wait! Wait!
ケバ!?　待て待て 待て待て！
（愛菜）うう… なん？
な… なんで俺なんだよ
Why me? Go drink with the guys from the tennis club!
連中[れんちゅう, れんじゅう]:company/lot|troupe, 飲む[のむ]:to drink|to smoke (tobacco)|to engulf||
テニサーの連中と
飲んでればいいだろ？
What did you say?
告る[こくる, コクる]:to confess (one's love)/to propose (marriage)/to ask out (on a date)
（愛菜）ああ？　なんでて？
なんであんたに告ったかちゃ？
Why did I ask you out?
That's not what I mean...
酒[さけ, ささ]:alcohol/sake
いや そうじゃなくて…
（伊織）さ… 酒くせえ
She smells like alcohol.
イケメン:good-looking guy/handsome man/hunk, 決まる[きまる]:to be decided/to be settled|to look good in (clothes)
あんたがイケメンやからに
決まっとろうもん
It's because you're hot.
（耕平）はあ？
（愛菜）テニサーだっちゃそうたい
Just like the tennis club.
They're all hot. That's why I joined.
イケメン:good-looking guy/handsome man/hunk
イケメンぞろいやけん
入ったっちゃ
I thought I'd be happy if I found a boyfriend.
彼氏[かれし]:boyfriend, 作る[つくる]:to make|to prepare (food)|to raise||, 幸せ[しあわせ, しやわせ]:happiness/good fortune/luck
彼氏ば作ったら幸せになれるけん
Then I'd have the perfect college life I dreamed of!
本[もと]:origin|base|cause||, 本[ほん]:book|this|main||, バラ色[バラいろ, ばらいろ]:rose-colour/rose-color, 生活[せいかつ]:living/life (one's daily existence)/livelihood
本で見たごたあ
バラ色の大学生活たい
But... Tell me!
やけど:burn/scald, 教える[おしえる]:to teach|to tell|to preach
やけど… あんた 教えて！
Why do I always end up like this?
なんで うちは
いつも こげなと～！
絡み[からみ]:linkage/entanglement/involvement, 絡み[がらみ]:about/concerning/related to
（伊織）か… 絡み酒か
-She's a drunk mess.
-All that makeup isn't helping.
絡みつく[からみつく]:to twine around/to twist around|to pester
（耕平）絡みつくほどにケバいな
I'm trying really hard, right?
頑張る[がんばる]:to persevere|to insist that|to remain in a place
うち 頑張っとうやろ？　ね？
-I'm trying really hard!
-Yeah.
ものすごい:earth-shattering/staggering|terrible, 頑張る[がんばる]:to persevere|to insist that|to remain in a place
ものすごく頑張っとうやろ？
（伊織）おう…
You were trying hard.
In a bad way.
確か[たしか]:sure|reliable|If I'm not mistaken, すごい:terrible/dreadful|amazing (e.g. of strength), 悪い[わるい]:bad|evil|unprofitable||, 悪い[にくい]:hateful/abominable|amazing, 意味[いみ]:meaning/significance
（耕平）確かにすごかったな
悪い意味で
I studied how to do makeup,
化粧[けしょう, けわい]:make-up/makeup/cosmetics, 研究[けんきゅう]:study/research/investigation
（愛菜）化粧もくさ
うちなりに研究して
and dressed up in clothes I'm not used to.
慣れる[なれる]:to get used to|to become skilled in|to become tame, 服装[ふくそう]:garments/attire
慣れん服装もして
一生懸命[いっしょうけんめい]:very hard/with utmost effort/with all one's might, 合わす[あわす]:to match (rhythm, speed, etc.)|to join together|to face||
一生懸命 ノリも合わして
I tried so hard to fit in,
and did things I didn't want to.
コール:(telephone) call/(telephone) ring
なんや！　コールやら
ＳＯＳＯやらって！
Movies and shows didn't teach me that!
映画[えいが]:movie/film, ドラマ:drama
映画とかドラマには
なかったやん そげなもん！
-Well...
-I bet.
（伊織）まあ…
（耕平）そうだろうな
（愛菜）うう～！
やのになんで―
Why does everyone make a fool out of me?
いかん:Italian warship, いかん:ancient headgear showing rank
みんなにバカにされな
いかんと～！
-Everyone?
-She's talking about the guys from Tinkerbell.
連中[れんちゅう, れんじゅう]:company/lot|troupe
みんな？
（伊織）ティンベルの連中か
Well, dressed like that...
格好[かっこう, かっこ]:shape|appearance|state||
まあ あの格好じゃな
With that much makeup,
they'd think she's weird.
色物[いろもの]:colored thing (clothing, fabric, paper, etc.) (coloured)|variety shows, 扱い[あつかい]:treatment/service, しかたない:it can't be helped/it's inevitable/it's no use
色物扱いでも
しかたないケバさだろ
Everyone said I was cute at first!
ばってん:cross mark/demerit mark/an X, ばってん:but/however/although, 最初[さいしょ]:beginning/outset/first
ばってんが みんな最初は
“かわいか～”って
Everyone was laughing!
思いっきり[おもいきり, おもいっきり]:with all one's strength/with all one's heart/resignation, 笑う[わらう]:to laugh|to smile|to sneer|
（耕平）いや 思いっきり
笑われてただろ！
（愛菜）ハッ！
（伊織）言っちまったな
You let it slip out.
Did I hurt you?
えっと:let me see/well/errr ..., 傷つく[きずつく]:to be wounded|to get hurt feelings|to get damaged
えっと… 傷ついたか
Even I already knew that.
くらい:dark/gloomy|dark (in colour), くらい:approximately/about|to (about) the extent that
うちも分かっとうよ そんくらい
At first, I didn't mind being treated as a joke.
最初[さいしょ]:beginning/outset/first, 扱い[あつかい]:treatment/service
最初はネタ扱いでもいいと
思ってた
As long as I could be friends and have fun,
I was okay with it.
仲よく[なかよく]:on good terms with/on cordial terms with|to make friends with, 楽しい[たのしい]:enjoyable/fun
仲よく楽しくできるなら
それでもって…
本望[ほんもう]:long-cherished ambition/satisfaction
（伊織）そうか…
（耕平）なら 本望だろ
-Really?
-Then isn't this what you wanted?
But at the drinking party after the pageant,
those guys told me...
連中[れんちゅう, れんじゅう]:company/lot|troupe, ミスコン:beauty contest to name Miss ..., 終わる[おわる]:to finish/to end/to close, 飲み会[のみかい]:drinking party/get-together
（愛菜）でも あの連中
ミスコン終わって飲み会になったら
十分[じっぷん, じゅっぷん]:10 minutes, 十分[じゅうぶん]:plenty|division into ten|perfectly, 笑う[わらう]:to laugh|to smile|to sneer|, 帰る[かえる]:to return|to leave|to get home
（工藤）もう十分笑ったから
帰っていいよ
"We've laughed enough.
You can go home now."
（愛菜）…って
（伊織･耕平）あ…
I shouldn't have tried so hard to change.
やっぱり:too/also|still, 無理[むり]:unreasonable|impossible|forcible||, 変わる[かわる]:to change|to move to|to be different, なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation
やっぱり 無理に変わろうとなんて
するんじゃなかった
No matter what I do,
I'm always getting laughed at.
結局[けっきょく]:after all|conclusion|ending of a game of Go, 笑う[わらう]:to laugh|to smile|to sneer|, 側[そば, そく]:near/close|third person, 側[がわ, かわ]:side (of something, or taking someone's side)/part|(watch) case
結局 私は何をしても
笑われる側で―
And they're the ones laughing at me.
笑う[わらう]:to laugh|to smile|to sneer|, 側[そば, そく]:near/close|third person, 側[がわ, かわ]:side (of something, or taking someone's side)/part|(watch) case
あいつらは笑う側なんだ
-Cakey, You...
-What are you talking about?
ケバ お前…
（伊織）何 言ってんだ
There's no one who's always laughing,
or always getting laughed at.
笑う[わらう]:to laugh|to smile|to sneer|
人を笑うだけ
笑う[わらう]:to laugh|to smile|to sneer|, なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation
人に笑われるだけなんてやつ
いるわけないだろ
But...
だけど！
I'll show you something interesting.
おもしろい:interesting/fascinating|amusing, 見せる[みせる]:to show/to display
おもしろいもんを見せてやる
あ…
IZU UNIVERSITY SPRING FESTIVAL
MEN'S BEAUTY PAGEANT
でかい:huge/big/gargantuan, キレる:to get angry/to snap/to blow one's top
（男性たち）いいぞ！　でかい！
キレてる！　でかい！
-Nice!
-Yeah!
You guys always mistake the male pageant
for a bodybuilding contest.
お前らのとこは―
毎年[まいとし, まいねん]:every year/yearly/annually, ボディービル:body-building, 大会[たいかい]:convention/tournament/mass meeting, 勘違い[かんちがい]:misunderstanding/wrong guess
毎年 男コンをボディービル大会と
勘違いしてないか？
Look who's talking!
お前らに言われたくねえよ
ハハハハ…
Up next!
次[つぎ]:next/following|stage, 次[じ]:next|hypo- (i.e. containing an element with low valence)|order, こちら:this way (direction close to the speaker or towards the speaker)/this direction|here (place close to the speaker or where the speaker is)
（司会者）はい！　次はこちら
I'm Kudo, the captain of the tennis club.
テニス:tennis, サークル:group with a common interest (e.g. students)/club (e.g. company sports club)/circle, 会長[かいちょう]:president (of a society)/chairman, よろしく:well/properly|best regards
テニスサークル ティンカーベル
会長の工藤です よろしく
Nice to meet you.
キャー:yikes!/eek!/ouch!
（女性たち）キャー！　工藤さん！
Can you say a few words about your club?
勝手に[かってに]:arbitrarily/of its own accord/voluntarily, どうぞ:please/kindly|by all means
んじゃ 勝手にＰＲをどうぞ
You're so casual.
適当[てきとう]:suitable/proper|noncommittal, 相手[あいて]:companion|other party|opponent (sports, etc.)
適当だな
（司会者）男相手っすから
Because I'm talking with a guy.
Kudo, you can do it!
頑張る[がんばる]:to persevere|to insist that|to remain in a place
（女性）工藤さん 頑張って！
Captain!
会長[かいちょう]:president (of a society)/chairman
会長！
You're going to win this year too!
今年[ことし, こんねん]:this year, 優勝[ゆうしょう]:overall victory/championship, 余裕[よゆう]:surplus/margin|composure
今年も優勝 余裕っすよ！
Of course!
I'm on a different level from the others!
当ったり前[あったりまえ]:natural/reasonable|usual, レベル:level/standard/amount
（工藤）当ったり前だろ
ほかとはレベルが違うんだよ
Next!
次[つぎ]:next/following|stage, 次[じ]:next|hypo- (i.e. containing an element with low valence)|order, 方[かた]:direction|person|method of||, 方[ほう]:direction|side (of an argument, etc.)|type||
（司会者）では次の方
美形[びけい, びぎょう]:beautiful form/beautiful shape/beauty
（女性）わあ
（女性）美形！
-A pretty boy!
-Why is he in a uniform?
制服[せいふく]:uniform
（女性）でも なんで制服？
Wasn't he with the naked idiots?
全裸[ぜんら]:nude, 連中[れんちゅう, れんじゅう]:company/lot|troupe, あんな:such (about something or someone distant from both speaker and listener, or about a situation unfamiliar to both speaker and listener)/so/that, あんな:Anna or Anwa era (968.8.13-970.3.25)
（工藤）
全裸バカ連中にいたか？
あんなやつ
I'm Kohei Imamura from Peek-a-Boo.
全裸[ぜんら]:nude, 連中[れんちゅう, れんじゅう]:company/lot|troupe, あんな:such (about something or someone distant from both speaker and listener, or about a situation unfamiliar to both speaker and listener)/so/that, あんな:Anna or Anwa era (968.8.13-970.3.25)
（工藤）
全裸バカ連中にいたか？
あんなやつ
Peek a Booの
今村(いまむら)耕平です
It doesn't matter.
I'm going to win anyway.
Peek a Booの
今村(いまむら)耕平です
優勝[ゆうしょう]:overall victory/championship, 変わる[かわる]:to change|to move to|to be different
まあいい
俺の優勝は変わらないさ
優勝[ゆうしょう]:overall victory/championship, 変わる[かわる]:to change|to move to|to be different
まあいい
俺の優勝は変わらないさ
優勝[ゆうしょう]:overall victory/championship, 変わる[かわる]:to change|to move to|to be different
まあいい
俺の優勝は変わらないさ
よろしく:well/properly|best regards, 願う[ねがう]:to desire|to beg|to have something done for oneself
よろしくお願いします
優勝[ゆうしょう]:overall victory/championship, 変わる[かわる]:to change|to move to|to be different
まあいい
俺の優勝は変わらないさ
A few words, please.
（司会者）じゃあ ＰＲを…
梓[あずさ, し]:Japanese cherry birch (Betula grossa)|yellow catalpa (Catalpa ovata)|Japanese mallotus (Mallotus japonicus)||
（司会者）あの…
（耕平）浜岡(はまおか)梓さん
Azusa Hamaoka!
Please go out with me,
not Captain Kudo from Tinkerbell!
会長[かいちょう]:president (of a society)/chairman, なんか:things like .../or something like that ... (often derogatory), なんか:something
ティンベルの
工藤会長なんかじゃなく―
つきあう:to associate with/to keep company with|to go along with, つきあう:to poke each other/to jab each other, くださる:to give/to confer|to kindly do for one
俺とつきあってください！
Imamura confessed his feelings!
突然[とつぜん]:abrupt/sudden/unexpected, 告白[こくはく]:confession|profession of love|confession of sins (e.g. the confessional)
（司会者）おーっと！
これは今村さん 突然の告白です！
目立つ[めだつ]:to be conspicuous/to stand out, やがる:verb suffix indicating hatred and contempt, or disdain for another's action
（工藤）チッ 目立ちやがって
He stands out.
How dare he use my name without asking?
勝手に[かってに]:arbitrarily/of its own accord/voluntarily
何 勝手に人の名前
使ってんだよ！
フッ…
No. Choose me instead.
願う[ねがう]:to desire|to beg|to have something done for oneself
（工藤）
いや 俺のほうにお願いします
Captain Kudo also confessed his feelings!
会長[かいちょう]:president (of a society)/chairman, 続く[つづく]:to continue|to continue (without a break)|to occur again and again||, 告白[こくはく]:confession|profession of love|confession of sins (e.g. the confessional)
（司会者）なんと！
工藤会長も続いて告白だ！
フッ…
Who is she going to choose?
一体[いったい]:...the heck (e.g. "what the heck?")|one object|one form||, どちら:which way/which direction|which one (esp. of two alternatives), 選ぶ[えらぶ]:to choose/to select
（司会者）さあ 一体
どちらを選ぶのか！
Whoa, it's Captain Kudo!
会長[かいちょう]:president (of a society)/chairman
（司会者）おおっ！　工藤会長だ！
Sorry things turned out like this.
悪い[わるい]:bad|evil|unprofitable||, 悪い[にくい]:hateful/abominable|amazing, ことになる:it has been decided (so) that/it has been arranged (so) that|it is the result (of)
悪いね
こんなことになっちゃって
People are all at different levels.
それぞれ:each/respectively, レベル:level/standard/amount
でもさ 人にはそれぞれ
レベルがあるわけだし
I bet there's a good match out there somewhere
for you too.
似合い[にあい]:well-matched/becoming/suitable
君には君なりの
お似合いの人がいるんじゃないかな
A good match?
似合い[にあい]:well-matched/becoming/suitable
お似合いの人… ねえ
フフフフフ…
（伊織･耕平）
ワハハハ！　ヒャハハ！
Too bad! I'm a man!
残念[ざんねん]:deplorable/bad luck/regret
残念でした 男です～！
へっ!?
Oh, really?
まさか:by no means/never!|something unexpected
いやあ そうですか！
まさか こんな僕が―
I never imagined I was a good match for Captain Kudo
from Tinkerbell!
天下[てんか, てんが]:the whole world|the whole country|society||, 会長[かいちょう]:president (of a society)/chairman, 似合い[にあい]:well-matched/becoming/suitable, なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation
天下のティンベル会長さんと
お似合いだなんて
That's great, Kitahara!
女装[じょそう]:female clothing/wearing female clothing/cross dressing (for a man)
よかったな 北原！
お前の女装は―
You guys are on the same level
when you're dressed up like a girl!
魅力[みりょく]:charm/fascination/glamour, 同格[どうかく]:the same rank/equality|apposition, らしい:seeming ... (expresses judgment based on evidence, reason or trustworthy hearsay)/appearing ...|-ish
この人の魅力と同格らしいぞ
というわけで
Peek a Boo 北原伊織
Iori Kitahara from Peek-a-Boo
is entering the male pageant!
飛ぶ[とぶ]:to fly/to soar|to jump, 参加[さんか]:participation
男コンに飛び入り参加します！
やがる:verb suffix indicating hatred and contempt, or disdain for another's action
ブッハッハ！
（寿）やりやがった あいつら！
They did it.
Hey, hold on! I--
お… おい！
ちょっと待て！　俺は…
What should I do?
The captain confessed his feelings for me!
会長[かいちょう]:president (of a society)/chairman, 告白[こくはく]:confession|profession of love|confession of sins (e.g. the confessional)
いや～ん どうしよう
私 会長さんに告白されちゃったあ
It hurts to lose,
but I'll step aside.
悔しい[くやしい, くちおしい]:vexing/annoying/frustrating, 身を引く[みをひく]:to resign/to abandon/to step aside
悔しいけど 俺は身を引くさ
Captain, I hope you two have a long happy life together!
会長[かいちょう]:president (of a society)/chairman, 末[うら]:top end/tip, 末[うれ]:new shoots/new growth (of a tree), 永い[ながい]:long (distance)|long (time)/lengthy, つきあい:association/socializing/socialising, くださる:to give/to confer|to kindly do for one
会長さん 末永く
おつきあいしてくださいねえ
ちょっと 何あいつ！
-Who are those guys?
-Kudo! What's going on?
どういう:somehow/how/in what way
工藤さん どういうこと!?
ち… 違うんだ これは！
No! This is--
Oh, right, captain.
会長[かいちょう]:president (of a society)/chairman, 十分[じっぷん, じゅっぷん]:10 minutes, 十分[じゅうぶん]:plenty|division into ten|perfectly, 笑う[わらう]:to laugh|to smile|to sneer|
ああ そうそう 会長
もう十分に笑ったんで…
We've laughed enough.
-You can go home now.
帰る[かえる]:to return|to leave|to get home
（伊織･耕平）帰っていいですよ
グウウ…
あ…
笑える[わらえる]:to be made to laugh
（伊織）なっ？　笑えるだろ
Pretty funny, right?
フフッ やってくれたわね
They did it!
ああ…
Congratulations on the women's beauty pageant
and the male pageant!
祝[いわい, ゆわい]:congratulation/congratulations/celebration, 祝[はふり, ほうり]:junior Shinto priest|Shinto priest/generic title for a member of the Shinto priesthood, ミスコン:beauty contest to name Miss ..., 冠[かんむり, かん]:cap (esp. a traditional cap worn with sokutai or ikan clothing)|top kanji radical|first verse of a haikai, etc.||, 冠[かぶり, こうぶり]:order/rank, 達成[たっせい]:achievement
（部員たち）祝！
男コン ミスコン ２冠達成！
いやー ハハハッ
Let's have a toast! A toast!
よっしゃ:gotcha/alrighty/got it, 乾杯[かんぱい]:toast|drinking one's glass dry|cheers
（時田）よっしゃ！
乾杯しようぜ 乾杯！
That's a washbowl.
洗面器[せんめんき]:wash basin/wash bowl (incl. portable bowl in a public bath)
（伊織）洗面器!?
You can't toast with that.
乾杯[かんぱい]:toast|drinking one's glass dry|cheers, 器[うつわ]:bowl/vessel|ability, 器[き]:device/instrument|vessel
（耕平）これ 乾杯できる
器じゃないんだが…
Hey.
あ… あのさ
（耕平･伊織）お？
I just want to--
えっと:let me see/well/errr ..., なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation
その… えっと…
なんて言うか…
How should I put this...
What's this?
何これ？
It's what it looks like.
とおり:avenue/street|coming and going, とおり:penetration (as of light)
見てのとおりだが
Do you want a bigger bucket?
もっと:(some) more/even more/longer, でかい:huge/big/gargantuan, 器[うつわ]:bowl/vessel|ability, 器[き]:device/instrument|vessel
もっとでかい器がいいのか？
そ… そうじゃなくて 私は！
That's not what I mean. I--
Drinking is better with lots of people!
やっぱ:too/also|still, 飲む[のむ]:to drink|to smoke (tobacco)|to engulf||, 大勢[おおぜい, たいぜい]:crowd of people/great number of people|in great numbers, 大勢[たいせい]:general trend/current thought
やっぱ飲むなら大勢だよな
Don't just stand there.
Sit down.
突っ立つ[つったつ]:to stick up (hair, etc.)|to stand up abruptly|to stand in one place, doing nothing in particular, 座る[すわる]:to sit|to assume (a position)|to hold steady
突っ立ってないで 座れよ
ん… フゥ…
（耕平･伊織）ん？
What? If you want to drink with me,
then you should just tell me.
一緒[いっしょ]:together|at the same time|same, 飲む[のむ]:to drink|to smoke (tobacco)|to engulf||, 素直[すなお]:obedient/meek|honest, なさる:to do
何よ 私と一緒に飲みたいなら
素直にそう言いなさいよ
全然[ぜんぜん]:not at all (with neg. verb)|wholly/entirely
いや 全然そんなことは
ないんだが
That's not what we mean.
Your makeup is thick as oil.
鬼神[きしん, きじん]:fierce god, ごとし:like/as if/the same as
鬼神のごとくケバい
Just drop it already!
やめる:to stop (an activity)/to cease|to cancel, やめる:to resign/to retire/to quit
だから それやめてよ
What's this? It's too strong.
濃い[こい]:deep (colour)|strong (flavour, smell, etc.)|thick (consistency)||
何これ 濃すぎ…
-Of course!
-You finished it?
ナンボのもんじゃー！
空ける[あける]:to open (a door, etc.)|to open (for business, etc.)|to empty||, 空ける[うつける]:to become empty (hollow)|to relax from a tense situation into a vacant or absent minded state
って空けてる!?
We've been trained well!
鍛える[きたえる]:to forge/to temper|to drill, 方[かた]:direction|person|method of||, 方[ほう]:direction|side (of an argument, etc.)|type||
鍛え方が違うんじゃ！
-They're good freshmen.
-Right?
いい１年だな
だろ？
（空手部員）うちにくれよ
-Give them to us.
-In your dreams.
寝言[ねごと]:sleep-talking|nonsense/gibberish, 寝る[ねる]:to lie down|to go to bed|to sleep (lying down)||, 言える[いえる]:to be possible to say/to be able to say
寝言は寝て言え
They were against it at the beginning.
でも あれだけ
イヤがっていたのにな
I was surprised when they asked me too.
頼む[たのむ]:to request|to call|to entrust to|, 驚く[おどろく]:to be surprised/to be astonished
私も 頼まれたときは驚いたよ
It turned out great in the end.
最高[さいこう]:most/highest|best, 結果[けっか]:result/consequence|coming to fruition
最高の結果だよな
Especially for her.
あの子にとってはね…
OKONOMIYAKI
You were in the beauty pageant, right?
You're so cute!
ミスコン:beauty contest to name Miss ...
（男性）君 ミスコンの子でしょ？
マジでかわいいね
Can I take your order?
注文[ちゅうもん]:order/request, 注文[ちゅうぶん]:annotation/explanatory note
ご注文は？
We have a yakitori stall.
Want to hang out later?
向こう[むこう]:opposite side|over there|the other party|, 焼き鳥[やきとり]:yakitori/chicken pieces (or sometimes beef or pork offal) grilled on a skewer
（男性）俺らさ 向こうで
焼き鳥やってんだけど―
遊ぶ[あそぶ, あすぶ]:to play|to mess about (with alcohol, gambling, philandery, etc.)|to be idle||, 遊ぶ[すさぶ]:to grow wild/to rage|to do something one enjoys
あとで遊びに来ない？
No thanks.
遠慮[えんりょ]:reserve|declining|forethought
遠慮します
Hey, we talked to her first!
先[さき]:previous|point (e.g. pencil)|head (of a line)||, 先[せん]:former/previous|first move (in go, shogi, etc.), 声かけ[こえかけ]:saying something (to someone)/greeting/approaching (someone)
おい 俺らが先に声かけたんだぞ
Don't be so cold!
つれない:cold/indifferent/unfriendly
そう つれないこと言わずにさ
Just let the other two handle the stall.
後ろ[うしろ]:back/behind/rear, 店番[みせばん]:store tending/salesperson, 任せる[まかせる]:to entrust (e.g. a task) to another|to passively leave to someone else's facilities|to leave to take its natural course||
後ろの２人に店番任せたら
ＯＫでしょ？
Stop!
かげん:(moon's) last quarter, かげん:lower limit|infimum
いいかげんに…
Do you have some business with her?
後輩[こうはい]:junior (at work, school, etc.)/younger people/younger student, 用[よう]:business|use|for the use of ...|
お前ら うちの後輩に
何か用か？
She looks unhappy.
見える[みえる]:to be seen|to look|to come, 見える[まみえる]:to have an audience|to face (an enemy)|to serve (esp. as one's wife)
イヤがってるように
見えるんだがねえ
Hey! Get lost!
散る[ちる]:to fall (e.g. blossoms, leaves)|to scatter|to disappear||
（時田）おら！　散れ散れ！
-Are you okay?
-Yeah.
大丈夫？
（千紗）はい…
Come on.
Those guys are useless.
まったく:really/truly|indeed
（寿）まったく あいつらは
なんのためにいるんだ
Hey! Get up, you guys!
起きる[おきる]:to get up|to wake up|to occur (usu. of unfavourable incidents)
（時田）ほら お前ら 起きろ！
It's time for the award ceremony.
表彰[ひょうしょう]:public acknowledgment/public acknowledgement/public recognition, 式[しき]:equation|ceremony|style|
（寿）表彰式の時間だぞ
Congratulations on winning!
おめでとう:congratulations!/an auspicious occasion!, おめでとう:Japanese sweets made with glutinous rice and azuki bean paste, ござる:to be
（司会者）ミスＣＩＵ
おめでとうございます
どうも…
Thanks.
ステージ:stage, パフォーマンス:performance (e.g. music, dance, pantomime, etc.), 最高[さいこう]:most/highest|best, 評判[ひょうばん]:fame/reputation|rumour (rumor)
ステージパフォーマンスが
最高だったと評判ですが
The audience liked your stage performance.
-What's wrong?
-She looks mad.
ずいぶん:very/extremely|contemptible, 不機嫌[ふきげん]:pout/displeasure/ill humor
（時田）なんだ？
（寿）ずいぶん不機嫌そうだな
Well, that makes sense.
そりゃ:very/extremely|that is
（梓）まあ そりゃそうだよね
-What?
-Why?
はて？
（寿）なんでだ？
Well, Chii-chan entered the pageant
just for Iori and the others.
だって ちーちゃんは
伊織たちのために―
しかたない:it can't be helped/it's inevitable/it's no use, ミスコン:beauty contest to name Miss ...
しかたなく
ミスコン出たのにさあ
But Iori and the others
worked hard for another girl.
なのに伊織たちは―
頑張る[がんばる]:to persevere|to insist that|to remain in a place
ほかの子のために
頑張ってたじゃない？
Chii-chan gets bothered by guys
そもそも:in the first place/to begin with|... the heck (e.g. "what the heck?"), 絡む[からむ]:to entangle|to pick a quarrel|to be involved with
そもそも ちーちゃんが
男に絡まれるのは―
because she entered the pageant,
ミスコン:beauty contest to name Miss ...
ミスコンに出たせいなのに
but no one helped her.
助ける[たすける]:to save|to help|to aid|, なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation, 腹が立つ[はらがたつ]:to get angry/to take offense/to take offence
自分のことは助けてくれないなんて
腹が立つよねえ
That'd make anyone mad.
Now that you mention it...
（時田）言われてみれば…
I'd feel mad too.
そりゃ:very/extremely|that is, 怒る[おこる, いかる]:to get angry|to tell someone off|to be angular
（寿）そりゃ 怒るわな
Who do you want to share this happiness with?
喜び[よろこび]:joy/delight/rapture, 伝える[つたえる]:to convey/to report/to transmit
（司会者）この喜びを
誰に伝えたいですか？
Yes. Well...
はい そうですね
I want to share it with my boyfriend,
酔いつぶれる[よいつぶれる]:to drink oneself dead drunk/to drink oneself unconscious
そこの 酔いつぶれている―
who's passed out drunk over there.
彼氏[かれし]:boyfriend, 伝える[つたえる]:to convey/to report/to transmit
私の彼氏に伝えたいです！
（一同）ん？
（司会者）はい？
Your boyfriend? Him?
彼氏[かれし]:boyfriend
（男性）か… 彼氏って
あいつのことか!?
He's a pervert!
変態[へんたい]:transformation/metamorphosis|abnormality
（男性）あれ 男コンの
変態じゃねえか！
I see. She used Iori to repel other guys.
なるほど:I see/That's right!/Indeed
なるほど 男よけに
伊織を使ったか
So now they're a couple?
恋人[こいびと]:lover/sweetheart
これで２人は恋人どうしってか？
Come on. Those two...
まったく:really/truly|indeed
まったく あの子らは…
どうするつもりなんだろうねえ
What are they going to do?
Kill him! Kill him! Kill him!
（観客たち）
殺せ！　殺せ！　殺せ！
DEEP BLUE AL FINE
KAYA MIZUKI
Here's your mic, Kitahara.
マイク:mike/mic/microphone
（耕平）ほれ 北原 マイク
（伊織）俺もかよ
Me, too...? All right, let's do this!
よっしゃ:gotcha/alrighty/got it
よっしゃ いくぜ！
-Yeah, sing your heart out.
-You guys seem to be having fun.
歌う[うたう]:to sing|to sing (one's praises in a poem, etc.)/to compose a poem
（寿）おお～ 歌え歌え！
ノリノリ:in high spirits
（時田）ノリノリだな
♪～
A fairytale whispers
In a fake world
Hiding in the complete darkness
I reach for the forbidden fruit
In my last days
Now I know the meaning of the song about hope
A broken gear will never stop again
Even if I were to lose everything
I'd still want you to know
Trapped in the sky so far away
I'm praying with ripped off wings
Because we span together
The vows of areppegio
If life sparkles only to the beat
of the resonating stars
I'll sacrifice everything
Till death do us apart
Cheers!
～♪
サンキュー:thank you
（一同）サンキュー！
Thank you!
I might just be imagining things.
気[き]:spirit|nature|motivation||, 気[げ]:seeming/giving the appearance of/giving one the feeling of, しれる:to become known/to come to light|to be known
（伊織）気のせいかもしれんが…
What? Kitahara?
なんだ 北原
視線[しせん]:one's line of sight/one's gaze/one's eyes (looking)
（伊織）みんなの視線が
いつもと違わないか？
Everyone's looking at me differently.
エヘヘヘ…
起きる[おきる]:to get up|to wake up|to occur (usu. of unfavourable incidents)
なに!?　今 俺に
何が起きてんの!?
What? Is something happening to me?
Am I going to die tomorrow?
明日[あした, あす]:tomorrow|near future
明日 死ぬの？
教える[おしえる]:to teach|to tell|to preach, 一体[いったい]:...the heck (e.g. "what the heck?")|one object|one form||, 起きる[おきる]:to get up|to wake up|to occur (usu. of unfavourable incidents)
教えてくれ！　一体
何が起きてるんだ！
Tell me! What's going on?
NEXT EPISODE
"TOO LATE"